Claire TAVERNIER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a highly motivated, well-organized and enthousiastic French young woman who completed a Master's degree in building engineering. I've been gaining a lot of experience during my previous jobs, but I decided to discover new horizons by travelling around the world, and I start with New Zealand. I'm reliable, motivated, with good learning abilities. I'm willing to learn new jobs, gain new and different experiences, and meet people.

CONTACT INFORMATION

①: 02.72.93.76.40

BIRTH DATE

21st March, 1991 Lille, North of France

SKILLS

COMUNICATION & INTERPERSONAL

- Good verbal and written communication skills : developed by animating meetings, negociating with customers, and writing reports during my previous jobs.
- Attentiveness and active listening ability: succeeded in assess people's needs and fulfill them appropriately.

PERSONAL MANAGEMENT

- Ability to handle pressure, and work well under stressful situations : developed during my previous jobs, which also required excellent adaptability.
- Good organizational skills : succeeded in managing my schedule, identify priorities. Ability to multi-tasks.
- Always paying attention to details: I like the rigor and the neat work.
 Analytical and synthetical mind: learnt during my studies and kept analyzing big files during my work experiences.

LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT

- Problem solving and decision making : achieved good results in previous jobs as engineer.
- Ability to learn from mistakes.

PERSONAL SKILLS & QUALITIES

- Good and fast learning abilities + willingness to learn.
- Physically active, healthy and fit : used to get up early and finish work late
- + daily sport practice.
- Smiling and optimistic; always with pleasant demeanor with colleagues and work teams.

LANGUAGES

English: Proficient TOEFL 597/650 Spanish: Conversational French: Native Language

OFFICE

Pack Office: Word, Excel, Powerpoint, MS Project, Outlook

Coding: HTML, JavaScript

Design: AutoCAD, SketchUp

French Cost estimating softwares:
Onaya, Progap

ATTIC+ (EasyKutch Q4)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 Working Holiday Visa - New Zealand

Kiwifruit picking – Te Puke – 3 weeks Tree Nursery job – 2 months

2017-2019

Cost Estimating and Building Engineer (Interdisciplinary) – Fayat Group – France

2 years

- Analysis of blueprints, specifications, proposals, and other construction documents : to prepare time, cost, materials, and labor estimates for ongoing projects.
- Researched and evaluated subcontractors based on price, quality, selection, service and support.
- Prepared the tender analysis sheet and presented it to the manager.
- Management of a team made up of architects and specialized engineers; to design new projects together.

2015-2017

Cost Estimating and Building Engineer - Angevin Group - France

2 years

- Specialized in structural work : preparing preliminary cost estimates of projects that are in conceptual stage.
- Responsible for submitting the tender on time.
- Won several tenders from 500 k€ to 25 M€.

2014

Building Engineer - Emergency Architects Foundation - Haïti

6 months

Construction site: Maternity, extension of a hospital.

- Design of structures, and site management: construction work, logistic and supplying, schedule, staffing, and budget control.
- Team work with a French architect, an Haïtian engineer, and a team of local workers.

2014 6 months

Site Engineer Internship – Paris, France

Construction site : 90 M€ Office renovation project.

- Budget management, Conformity and quality check,
- Responsible for the guarantee of energy performance, team work with Italian subcontractor.

2013 3 months

Site Engineer Internship - Paris, France

Social collective housing renovation projects : from 10 M€ to 120 M€.

- Management of subcontractors team,
- Conformity and quality check.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 Labor Internship – Estelí, Nicaragua

Humanitarian mission :

- Sponsor searching during the year before leaving,
- On the spot : builder of houses (blocks, posts, beam, floors, carpentry) ; Team work with Nicaraguan builder.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

2014 Master Degree in building engineering

Ecole Spéciale des Travaux Publics, et du Bâtiment (Top French civil engineering school), Paris, France

2008 - 2011 Three years intensive courses to prepare nationwide competitive exams in scientific engineering

schools

Henri Wallon School, France

2008 High School Diploma, Scientific option – with upper honors

Paul Hazard High School, France

PERSONNAL INTERESTS / ACTIVITIES

Sports - **Hiking**: every year during holidays

- Fencing: regional competitions in France- Fitness / Bodybuilding: daily practice

Music - **Piano** : Since the age of 5 – several concerts

- Euphonium : with Brass bands

Travel Turkey, New York, Norway, Morocco, Croatia,

Madera, Italy, Haïti, Reunion Island, Thailand,

Portugal, Kyrgyrzstan...

REFERENCEES

Only French references for the moment : Available on requests.